Guide to the U.S. Civil War Photographs Collection, 1861-1865 MS 476
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
U.S. Civil War Photographs Collection
1861-1865
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Brady, Mathew B.
MS 476
0.1 Linear Feet (84 photographs)
These photographs taken during the U.S. Civil War reflect a wide range of battles and sites, although not all are represented. The collection includes 84 photographs mounted on 8″ × 91/2″ boards, many labelled with caption information. The photographs were taken by a variety of photographers, including Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner, and many have been published in "The Photographic History of the Civil War" or which are also available through the National Archives.
Biographical / Historical
These photographs document the U. S. Civil War, 1861-1865.
Scope and Contents
These photographs taken during the Civil War reflect a wide range of battles and sites, although not all are represented. The collection includes 84 photographs mounted on 8″ × 91/2″ boards, many labelled with caption information.
The photographs were taken by a variety of photographers, including Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner. Whenever possible they have been identified as to artist by comparison with "The Photographic History of the Civil War" and The Mathew B. Brady Collection of Civil War Photographs cited at the end of the list.
The "Photo" numbers are those which appear in pencil on the photograph itself, and the "(PHCW) Page #" reflects the page number of "The Photographic History of the Civil War" (PHCW) on which the photograph was published. Mathew B. Brady photographs are also assigned numbers by the National Archives, B-xxx, and will be so designated here.
Identifications made May, 1978. Margaret R. Olvey
Inventory divisions follow those used in "The Photographic History of the Civil War." main stacks E468.7.M5
Identifications of Mathew B. Brady photogaphs made by comparison to The Mathew B. Brady Collection of Civil War Photographs microfilm, in four reels from the National Archives, Film E 468.7 .B8.
Identifications of other photographs made by comparison to "The Photographic History of the Civil War." ed. Francis Trevelyan Miller. New York. Review of Reviews Co. 1911-12. 10 vols. reprinted in 5 vols. by T. Yoseloff, New York, 1957.
Access Restrictions
No access restrictions; this material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. George R. Brown, 1958.
Related Material
Flyleaf, v. 5:2
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center inside the vault.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865)
Document Types
photographs
- Series I: Portraits
  - Scene in Pleasant Valley, MD. Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 24." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218651; PHCW Page # 161 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 1)
  - Breaking Camp, Brandy Station, Negative by James Gardner, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 63. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1864-05; 218698; PHCW Page # 35 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 2)
  - Photo of house with 20ish people in front on the balcony and front step. (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 3)
  - Photo of small house with 6 generals/army officers in front of it. On front porch, mostly holding swords. (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 4)
  - General Ambrose Burnside, Different Pose, with staff - Burnside sitting surrounded by ~20 men mostly standing. Outside of a tent. (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 5)
  - Solider and Citizen Before the Appomattox Court House. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 9: Poetry and Eloquence, Pg. 127., 218652; PHCW Page # 126 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 6)
  - The Forces at last Join Hands. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 3: The Decisive Battles, Pg. 89. (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 7)
  - McLean's House, Appomattox Court-House, Va. Where the Capitulation was Signed Between Generals Grant and Lee, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 99. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War. Also Pg. 109 of War Photographs Taken on the Battlefields of the Civil War - Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner., 1865-04; 218639; Brady # B-6333. (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 8)
  - Aiken House, Petersburg, Virginia, 1864-08; 218694; PHCW Page # 197 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 9)
  - Photograph Taken While Government Provision Trains were Entering Petersburg after Evacuation. Pg. 99 - War Photographs Taken on the Battlefields of the Civil War Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner., 1865; 218716; PHCW Page # 278 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 10)
  - Photograph Taken at Grapevine Bridge over the Chickahominy. Pg. 40, War Photographs Taken on the Battlefields of the Civil War Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner., 218715; PHCW Page # 279 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 11)
  - Castle Murray, Near Auburn, Va., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 47. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-11; 218681; PHCW Page # 243 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 12)
  - Dedication of Monument on Bull Run Battle-Field. Negative by W. Morris Smith, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 100. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-06; 218647; PHCW Page # 266 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 13)
  - Scouts and Guides to the Army of the Potomac, Berlin, Md. Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 28. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-10; 218661; PHCW Page # 19 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 14)
  - Photograph Taken Shortly After the Battle of Chancellorsville - Major-General Joseph Hooker and Staff. War Photographs Taken on the Battlefields on the Civil War Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner., 1863; 218708; PHCW Page # 109 (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 15)
  - Portrait of 7 soldiers standing or sitting with weapons on a porch (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 16)
  - Portrait of 19 men sitting or standing in front of a staircase (Box 1, Folder 1, Photograph 17)
- Series II: Battles, 218686
  - Photograph Taken While Skeletons of Dead Soldiers Were Being Removed Several Months After Battle of Cold Harbor. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, Plate 94, 218636 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 1)
    General note
    Photographs in this publication attributed to Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner.
  - Dead Among the Rocks of Little Round Top on Gettysburg Battlefield, Pg. 66, War Photographs Taken on Battlefields of the Civil War: Mathew B. Brady and Alexander Gardner., 218722; PHCW Page #71 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 2)
  - A Sharpshoot's Last Sleep, Gettysburg, Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 40., 1861-07; 218703; PHCW Page # 249 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 3)
  - Home of a Rebel Sharpshooter, Gettysburg, Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 41. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1863-07; 218649; PHCW Page # 205 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 4)
  - The Carnage of Bloody Angle. Photographic History of the Civil War Miller in Ten Volumes, Volume 2: Two Years of Grim War, Pg. 247, 218725; PHCW Page # 43 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 5)
  - Inspection of Troops at Cumberland Landing, Pamunkey, Va., Negative by Wood & Gibson, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 16. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-05; 218724; Brady # B-6336. PHCW Page # 51 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 6)
  - Ruins of Gaines' Mill, Va., Negative by John Reekie, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 93. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-04; 218714; PHCW Page # 342 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 7)
  - Wagon Park, Brandy Station, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 64. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-05; 218685; PHCW Page # 100 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 8)
  - Antietam Bridge, Md. Alex Gardner, Photographer, plate 19. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-09; 218723; Brady # B-7199. PHCW Page # 54 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 9)
  - Interior of Breastworks on Round Top, Gettysburg. Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 38. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-07; 218702; Brady # B-6357. PHCW Page # 251 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 10)
  - Ruins of Stone Bridge, Bull Run, Va. negative by Barnard & Gibson, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 7. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-03; 218721; PHCW Page # 138 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 11)
  - Gettysburg, negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 35. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-07 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 12)
  - Interior View of Confederate Line at Gracie's Salient, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 86. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1865-05; 218637 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 13)
  - A Harvest of Death, Gettysburg, negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 36. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-07; 218707; PHCW Page # 241 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 14)
  - Field Where General Reynolds Fell, Gettysburg, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner Plate 37. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-07; 218705; PHCW Page # 242 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 15)
  - The Abandoned Stronghold. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 2: Two Years of Grim War, Pg. 325., 1862; 218699; PHCW Page #325 (Box 1, Folder 2, Photograph 16)
- Series III: Fortifications, 218672
  - The Pulpit, Fort Fisher, N.C., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 79. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book, 1865-01; 218642; Brady # B-6358. (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 1)
  - The Biggest Gun of all - the 20-inch Monster for Which No Target Would Serve, Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 5: Forts and Artillery, Pg. 138., 218678; PHCW Page # 137 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 2)
  - Ruins of Norfolk Navy Yard, Va., negative by J. Gardner, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 18: Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1864-12; 218671; PHCW Page # 73 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 3)
  - Motor Dictator, Front of Petersburg, Negative by David Knox, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 55. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1864-10; 218695; PHCW Page # 186 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 4)
  - Hard Mount Headquarters, Army of the Potomac, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 55. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 218658; PHCW Page # 224 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 5)
  - Quaker Guns, Centreville, Va., negative by Barnard & Gibson, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 6. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-03; 218719; PHCW Page # 163 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 6)
  - A Courier at Headquarters. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 4: The Calvary, Pg. 209., 218683; PHCW Page # 209 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 7)
  - Headquarters Maj. Gen., George G. Meade, During the Battle of Gettysburg, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 43. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1863-07; 218700; PHCW Page # 261 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 8)
  - Ruins of Arsenal, Richmond, Va. Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 91. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-04; 218641; Brady #s B-466, 749… (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 9)
  - Fort Fisher: Effect of the Naval Bombardment of December, 1864. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 5: Forts and Artillery, Pg. 267., 1864-12; 218674; PHCW Page # 267 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 10)
  - Three First Traverses on Land End, Fort Fisher, N. C. Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 78. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-01; 218675; PHCW Page # 265 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 11)
  - Quarters of Men in Fort Sedgwick, Generally Known as Fort Hell, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 83., 1865-05; 218677; PHCW Page # 217 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 12)
  - Pontoon Bridge, Across the James, Negative by James Gardner, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 69. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1864-06; 218676; PHCW Page # 239 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 13)
  - Pontoon Bridge, Across the Potomac, at Berlin, MD., Alex Gardner, photographer, Plate 25. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1862-11; 218711; PHCW Page # 56 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 14)
  - View of the Interior of Fort Stedman, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 84. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-05; 218692; PHCW Page # 206 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 15)
  - Dutch Gap, James River, Va. Negative by J. Reekie, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 87." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-03; 218640; Brady #s B-4057, 414, 426, 676… (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 16)
  - Fortifications on Heights of Centreville, Va., negative by Barnard & Gibson, positive by A. Gardner, Plate 5. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-03; 218718; PHCW Page # 166 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 17)
  - Fortifications at Manassas, Negative by Barnard & Gibson, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 11. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1862-03; 218693; PHCW Page # 203 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 18)
  - The Tredegar Works for Heavy Guns, Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 5: Forts and Artillery, Pg. 307, 218673; Brady # B-4867. PHCW Page # 307 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 19)
  - Federal Battery No. 1 in front of Yorktown, Virginia, 1862-05; 218679; PHCW Page # 23 (Box 1, Folder 3, Photograph 20)
- Series IV: Prisons and Hospitals, 218662
  - Slave Pen, Alexandria Virginia, negative by Wm. R. Powell, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 2, from Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1863-08; 218643; Brady #s B-4867, 5119, 6334. (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 1)
  - Provost Marshal's Office, Aquia Creek, Va., negative T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 46. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-02; 218667; PHCW Page # 187 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 2)
  - Fairfax Court House, Va., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 3. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1863-08; 218684; PHCW Page # 167 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 3)
  - View on the Appomattox, Near Campbell's Bridge, Petersburg, Va., Mau, 1865, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 82. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War. (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 4)
  - Old Capital Prison, Washington D.C., Negative by Wm. R. Powell, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 90. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218669; PHCW Page # 67 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 5)
  - Libby Prison, Richmond, Va. Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 89." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-04; 218668; PHCW Page # 91 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 6)
  - The 'Shebang', or Quaters, U. S. Sanitary Commission, Brandy Station, Negative by J. Gardner, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 51. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-11; 218663; PHCW Page # 335 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 7)
  - Medical Supply Boat, Appomattox Landing, Va., Negative by J. Reekie, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 72. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-01; 218665; PHCW Page # 227 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 8)
  - Castle Thunder Provost Prison, Richmond, Virginia, 218666; PHCW Page # 199 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 9)
  - Different view of Field Hospital, 2nd Division, 2nd Army Corps, Brandy Station, Virginia, 218664; PHCW Page # 267 (Box 1, Folder 4, Photograph 10)
- Series V: Buildings, 218654
  - High Bridge, Crossing the Appomattox, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 98. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book., 218689; PHCW Page # 311 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 1)
  - Gateway of Cemetery, Gettysburg, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 39. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-07; 218701; PHCW Page # 259 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 2)
  - Map photographing - Alexander Gardner: Trees cut down with house/cabin and tent, 218660 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 3)
  - U.S. Military Telegraph Construction Corps, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 62. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book, 1864-04; 218726; PHCW Page # 41 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 4)
  - Army Repair Shop, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 70, Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1864-02; 218659; PHCW Page # 41 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 5)
  - Pontoon Bridge, Across the Rappahannock, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 23., 1863-05; 218709; PHCW Page # 91 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 6)
  - Poplar Grove Church, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive Alexander Gardner, Plate 74, Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1865-02; 218657; PHCW Page # 257 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 7)
  - Battery Wagon, From top Petersburg, Negative by David Knox, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 73. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1864-09; 218656; PHCW Page # 353 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 8)
  - Dunker Church Battle-Field of Antietam, Md., Negative by J. Gardner, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 21. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218650; PHCW Page # 189 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 9)
  - Charles Court-House, Va., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by Alexander Gardner, Plate 68. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War, 1864-06; 218682; PHCW Page # 223 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 10)
  - Marshall House, Alexandria, VA., August, 1862, Negative by Wm. R. Pywell, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 1. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218713; Brady #s B-5193, 6335, 5294. PHCW Page # 351 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 11)
  - Ruins of Richmond and Petersburg Railroad Bridge, Across the James, Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 88. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218644; Brady #s B-370, 1737, 1929, 2734, 3321, 4863, 5566. (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 12)
  - Moore House, Yorktown, Va., Negative by Wood & Gibson, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 15." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-05; 218717; PHCW Page # 269 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 13)
  - Supporting the Pursuit of Lee's Army. Photographic History of the Civil War, Miller, Volume 3: The Decisive Battles, Pg. 304., April, 1865; 218690; PHCW Page # 305 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 14)
  - Chesterfield Bridge, North Anna, VA., negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 66" Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1864-05; 218697; PHCW Page # 71 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 15)
  - Ruins at Manassas, negative by Barnard & Gibson, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 9. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-03; 218712; PHCW Page # 41 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 16)
  - Appomattox Station, Va., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 97. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-04-08; 218688; PHCW Page # 313 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 17)
  - View on Canal, Near Crenshaw's Mill, Richmond, Va. Alex Gardner, Photographer, Plate 92. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-04; 218646; Brady #s B-14, 702, 737, 798, 4820, 4042. 306 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 18)
  - Fredericksburg, Virginia, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, plate 30. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 218727; PHCW Page # 26 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 19)
  - Quarles' Mill, North Anna, Va. Alex. Gardner, Photographer, Plate 67." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-05 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 20)
  - Stone Church, Centreville, Va. negative by Barnard & Gibson, Positive by A. Gardner, plate 4. From Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1862-03; 218720; PHCW Page #149 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 21)
  - Headquarters New York Herald, Army of the Potomac, Bealton, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 56. Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1863-09; 218655; Brady # B-5512. PHCW Page # 285 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 22)
  - Wagon with Logs in trunk (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 23)
  - Johnson's Mill, Petersburg, Va., Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 80." Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the Civil War., 1865-05; 218687; PHCW Page # 335 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 24)
  - View of the Petersburg Gas Works, Negative by T. H. O'Sullivan, Positive by A. Gardner, Plate 81., 1865-04; 218691; PHCW Page # 274 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 25)
  - Federal Building with Flag pole (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 26)
  - Washington Monument, Richmond, Viriginia. 228, 218648; Possibly Brady # B-4815. PHCW Page # 228 (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 27)
  - Federal Building with Benefit Florence Sign outside (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 28)
  - Antietam Battlefield, Burnside's Bridge, different view. (Box 1, Folder 5, Photograph 29)